- You all set for tomorrow?
- 12:00 sharp. We're ready.
You talking about lunch?
- That sounds civilized.
- You got the memo.
We're talking about
the mandatory seminar
on budget protocols.
Oh. Have fun with that.
You're coming too, Jane.
[Jane]
'You're joking, of course.'
I-I don't do seminars.
Well, you do when
they're mandatory.
- No, I'm a consultant.
- Too bad.
They're checking attendance.
You have to sign in.
Oh, okay then, um..
"Patrick Jane."
Just, uh, copy that down for me.
Forge your signature?
That's against the rules.
Is it?
I'm not gonna tell anyone.
- Jane.
- Lisbon.
I understand your
precarious emotional state
given you've just gotten your
job back and your sensitivity
to the bureaucrats that
are watching your every move.
- They are.
- Yes, but that's your thing.
I gotta be me.
I can't change myself.
No, but you can change
where you are tomorrow at 12.
It's not gonna happen.
You think this is funny?
We got a missing child,
Marin County.
Snatched from a school
bus stop two hours ago.
The mother asked for us.
Rigsby will meet us downstairs.
Grace, set up a command post.
Liaise with the Marin sheriff.
Tell him we're on our way.
- It's good to have her back.
- Mm. Yes, it is.
[instrumental music]
Our missing boy,
nine years old, only child.
Another kid was walking to
the bus stop, he saw a vehicle
peeling out with our boy
Conner Flint in it.
'The man behind the wheel
was wearing a hoodie.'
- Description on the vehicle?
- Big and dark.
- The kid's eight years old.
- Is it a custody kidnapping?
The woman was widowed two years
ago. Her husband died of cancer.
Looks like there's family money.
There's no ransom demand yet.
- Start with the bus stop?
- Yeah, you and Cho.
Jane and I will
question the family.
- What's the mother's name?
- 'Elizabeth Flint.'
[indistinct chattering]
[gasps]
Patrick! Oh!
- Thank God you're here.
- Hello, Beth.
[Beth sighs]
I have everything
ready for the reading.
I'll do everything
I can to help, I promise
but, uh, I need to you know,
I'm-I'm not a psychic anymore.
What? Wh...what do you mean?
Well, I mean, I'm not...well,
I-I never really was a psychic.
No, I'm not...no...
what are you saying?
No, I-I know that-that
you-you are. Look, you..
Please help me find Conner. You
have a connection with him--
- Beth.
- So...can we get started?
- I have this locket and--
- Excuse me, ma'am. I'm sorry.
- I'm so happy you're here.
- Ma'am.
- Would you excuse us?
- I'm glad you're here.
I-I'm sorry.
[exhales deeply]
She's an old client.
Uh, yeah.
We don't have
time for this mess.
That boy is out
there somewhere
and this psychic
stuff is a distraction.
I think you'd better leave.
Can't say I disagree.
Hello. Is Beth inside?
And you are..
[Lisbon]
'I'm Agent Lisbon.
We're with the CBI.'
Oh. Nathan Glass.
When Beth told me about Conner
I came immediately
to see what I could sense.
- Sense?
- I'm Beth's spiritual advisor.
- A psychic?
- She's expecting me.
Excuse me.
Second thought.
[theme music]
[indistinct chattering]
[dog barking]
Forensics found the kid's
phone in the bushes over there.
- Has the amber alert gone live?
- 'Yep. No tips yet.'
Deputies shut down the streets
after Conner disappeared.
There's some unpaved
trails in the woods
'that a vehicle
could get through.'
'We got checkpoints up, but..'
[Cho on phone]
We get a ransom demand yet?
No, and I don't
think we're going to.
There've been two other
abductions in the bay area
with a similar MO,
young boys snatched
while waiting for the bus.
But there were balloon animals
found at those scenes.
'They think that's how
the guy lured the kids.'
What happened to those boys?
ME estimates both
boys were strangled
approximately 12 hours
after they vanished.
Which means Conner has
only about eight hours.
[indistinct chattering]
I talked with Conner
about safety...all the time.
You know,
i-if a stranger grabs you
just kick, punch, scream,
anything to get away.
You know, I-I...I told him.
Shh. It's not your fault.
You taught him well.
Everyone who knows you
knows that you're a perfect mom.
How well did you know Conner?
Beth and I have worked
together for two years
'since her husband passed over.'
I feel like I've
watched him grow up.
Conner's such a great kid.
He's kind and funny and smart.
Beth, uh, did Conner always
take the bus to school?
It-it was Deke's idea,
uh, my brother.
Um, he thought
it would do Conner good.
Deke Hutton. He lives here.
Um...yes, ever since James died
'and-and I-I agreed
with him...about the bus.'
You know, I-I didn't want
Conner to grow up sheltered.
And Jonathan supported it too.
Jonathan is my,
um, my grown stepson.
He's, um, Conner's brother.
You know, he...
actually, he owns this house.
He's letting Conner and me
stay as long as we want.
Nice guy.
And where are
Deke and Jonathan now?
Um, they're with
our...our bankers.
If...if this is, uh,
a-a ransom-type thing, I..
we'd need to
have a lotta cash.
Yes, ifit is.
You-you...you can find him.
You-you, you and Nate,
you can work together.
'I know that you can--'
I know you can see
where he is, so..
...so-so that we-we
can bring him home.
Mr. Glass, would you excuse us?
Beth, don't worry.
I'll be outside, okay?
Okay.
Beth, please have a seat.
'Okay. Just breathe and relax.'
I need you to hear this...okay?
I'm not a psychic.
I never was.
I was a con artist.
I took your money,
and I told you lies.
- No, they-they weren't lies.
- Yes.
No. No. You-you
know they weren't.
No, i-if you're,
if you're not a psychic
then-then why are you
working with the police?
Ma'am, Mr. Jane
is working with us
because he is
an excellent investigator.
He's gonna be very helpful
in this. I promise.
I understand.
I-it must be a terrible burden,
the gift you have.
Of course you have to deny it.
I mean...even St. Peter
denied who he was three times.
Beth, there are no such thing
as psychics. This man Glass--
- It must be awful..
- He's a fraud too.
...knowing what's gonna happen.
I mean, if..
who's gonna live
and who's gonna die.
But please, please..
...pleasedon't deny your gift.
Not now. No.
You have to help me.
You gotta help me find Conner.
Here, look, I have this locket
and it has
his-his first haircut.
Look. Touch this.
See if you can get a sense.
- If this is--
- No, Beth.
This is from his
first haircut and..
- Touch this.
- No.
- Mrs. Flint.
- No! My, no!
My son...no! My son is missing.
[sobbing]
My son is missing! You have
to find him! You have to.
Mrs. Flint, please, let's just
sit down for a minute, please..
Calm down, okay? It's okay.
Patrick...I..
[sobbing]
Sources inside the Marin County
sheriff's department confirm
that Conner Flint, age nine
was snatched from his
school bus stop this morning.
No ransom demand
has yet been made.
A CBI spokesman
told this reporter
that all leads and tips
are being pursued
and that police are looking
for a possible suspect.
[woman on TV]
'However, when we asked them
to give further information'
'about who that suspect
might be, they refused.'
[man on TV]
'Thanks, Debra. Keep us posted.'
They'd go nuts if we told them
we suspected someone who's
murdered two other boys.
They're calling this
guy the balloon man.
Media. Vultures.
I'm checking into
pedophiles released
before the first killing,
looking for any
escalating violence.
Nothing so far.
Good. Anything from forensics
yet on trace from the bus stop?
Yeah, they say it's gonna
take at least 24 hours.
[sighs]
Okay. A serial offender.
This changes our whole play.
We gotta work
three cases to find him.
I'll check everything
the local cops already checked.
- Maybe they missed something.
- Work fast.
Mr. Flint, when was the last
time you saw your brother?
Uh, this morning
at breakfast.
We have breakfast together,
Beth, Conner, Deke, and me.
Conner had-had French toast.
Everything was fine.
I-I...I can't believe this.
[sighs]
How's-how's Beth doing?
Mm. Not great.
How long ago did
she marry your father?
Um, 12 years ago.
How did you feel about that?
I like and respect Beth, if
that's what you're getting at.
She's no wicked stepmother. I
care deeply for her and Conner.
If you care,
how come you let her
throw her money away
on this, uh, psychic?
Never bothered you
when it was you, Mr. Jane.
Yeah, I heard about you.
You nearly
squeezed Beth dry.
- And you are..
- Conner's uncle.
- Deke Hutton.
- Mm.
And you should've gone to jail,
you miserable sleazebag.
Well, nice to meet you too. I'm
not sure that I'm a sleazebag.
- That's enough.
- 'Miserable--'
We're here to find
Conner, got it?
Yeah. Sorry.
We're trying to put
together Conner's morning.
You dropped him off at
his school bus stop, right?
Yeah.
And you left him there alone?
He wanted it that way.
He wanted to show
his independence.
The other kids
would make fun of him
if he had somebody
waiting with him.
It's such a safe neighborhood.
He's always been fine.
So it was routine for you
to, uh, leave him
alone there?
Yeah. I told you. He wanted
it that way. Beth agreed.
If you think you'll pin this
on me, then you're mistaken!
Typical addict, misdirected
anger, persecution complex.
- Excuse me. I'm not an addict.
- Yes, you are. You both are.
You, gambling, hence
the purple smudge
on your thumb from
the ticket stubs at the track
and your need to live off
your sister's money
and you, antidepressants,
the shiny skin, the dyspepsia.
Some deep emotional need...not
being fulfilled, I would guess.
- Are we done here?
- Just getting started.
Thank you. We are.
[sighs]
[Deke]
Jerk.
Nice work.
[Rigsby]
'I dug up possible witnesses'
'in the first two cases.'
A power company guy
near the first killing
a teacher on the second
and a neighbor
of the second kid, like that.
Long shots. We'd do
better using that psychic.
Thought you liked
that spiritual stuff.
What about your
psychic cousin Yolanda?
Yolanda's real.
That guy's a fake.
- Good luck.
- You too.
Mr. Walton, we understand
the day the first boy vanished
you were checking a downed
power line on Martindale Road.
Yep. That's what my records say.
You know,
funny story about that.
They told me it was
a damaged overhead conductor.
Turns out it was
a blown transformer.
[chuckles]
Can you imagine? I could have
taken out the entire grid.
Think back.
Did you happen
to notice anything
on your way to or from that job
or maybe this child?
I'm not sure.
What's the kid's name?
Reggie Miranda.
He was the second victim.
Your car got a flat tire
on Teer's Hill.
Remember seeing
him at the bus stop?
Well, that wasn't
a flat tire per se.
More like, uh,
I told my girlfriend that
so we'd be stranded
she could get
a little friendlier
which she did,
if you know what I mean.
High five.
Come on. Give it up.
As I was leaving,
there was this black SUV
nearly ran me off the road
which reminds me
of another funny story..
Black SUV,
power company guy says
there was a ding
in the bumper.
Great. That narrows it down.
I think I can help you.
Take my hand.
I want a baby
more than anything.
Shh. I know.
Just...listen.
[sighs]
[exhales deeply]
In the beyond, Beth,
I see your baby.
'He's the light of your life.'
He? It's a boy.
Yes, a boy.
[exhales deeply]
His name is Conner.
Conner? That-that's
my father's name.
[chuckles]
A beautiful baby boy.
[chuckling]
'That was Conner's favorite
when he was a baby.'
He doesn't play with
it anymore, but I just
I can't throw it out now.
You understand.
Yeah. Here.
[sighs]
You know, Deke thinks
I'm an idiot about you.
Jonathan probably does too,
but he's too nice to say so.
You know,
but they weren't there.
They didn't, they didn't
see your powers at work.
There was nothing to see.
Women that are trying hard
to have babies often succeed
and when they do, there's
a 50/50 chance that it's a boy.
- It was just a good guess.
- No, you knew.
And what was I to say, you
were never gonna have a child?
Nobody wants
a gloomy psychic.
You had a child.
You lost her.
I-I read about it
in the papers.
- Murdered?
- Yeah.
[whispers]
I'm sorry.
Yeah.
- That's why you deny your gift?
- No.
Is Conner dead too?
Please. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry about before,
but please tell me.
- It's just us right now--
- I-I can't tell you.
[panting]
Beth. Oh, thank God.
I had a flash, and, uh..
[Lisbon]
Mr. Glass, I told
you to stay downstairs.
Beth, I think I saw Conner.
It was just a flash,
but, um..
Oh, please, Beth,
don't listen to this nonsense.
[Beth]
'Where's he? Where-where
is he? Is-is he alive?'
I don't know.
It was just a split second.
I need a vessel
or...Conner's favorite.
From when he was a baby,
of course.
Of course. Nice read.
- Mr. Glass, let's go.
- No, Agent Lisbon.
Please, no, Nate,
tell me. Go ahead.
Beth, it's alright. I'm here.
[sighs]
I need you to
think with me, okay?
I need you to think of Conner.
He's filling your heart.
He's filling your mind..
[inhales]
Yes.
Yes, I see him.
[Glass]
'He's very still.'
He's dead?
No.
He's alive.
Sleeping.
[shouting]
Conner, wake up!
Can you hear me?
Your mother's here!
He's saying,
"I love you, mo mo."
Mo mo. That's what he called me.
He calls me mo mo.
Oh! Oh!
- 'Thank you.'
- Yeah.
[sighs]
- Hallelujah.
- Mmm.
Amen.
Jonathan! Jonathan!
Jonathan, he's alive.
Conner's alive. Nate sensed him.
Oh, Nate sensed
something alright...money.
- You think Glass was faking?
- 'Course he was.
- Money-grubbin' bastard.
- No, no, no.
It was Conner.
He-he called me mo mo.
That-that's his nickname
for me. N-nobody knew that.
That's exactly how
the trick works, Beth.
You use a detail that
no one could possibly know
except Nate Glass did know.
He's been in and out
of this house for two years.
No, I don't think
he knew that name. No..
How much have you paid him
since your husband died?
How much more will you give him
since he can sense your son?
And then, if Conner dies
and Glass can contact his spirit
what won't you give?
Hey, don't say that.
Don't you dare.
You're sick.
Nate would never do that.
Of course, he would. Believe me.
[chuckles]
He would.
No, you don't know, Patrick.
Apparently, you
don't know anything.
My son called out for me.
He's alive,
but you won't believe it
because you can't
stand what you are
so you run away
from yourself
and you hate anybody like you,
and hurt anybody who cares.
That doesn't mean
I'm psychic.
It just means you're
gullible and desperate.
What is wrong with you
that you treat people like that?
Oh, you should've
seen me ten years ago.
[birds chirping]
It's beautiful, huh?
It's all state
forests that way.
Nothing but bears
and deer...elk.
Hmm.
You're pretty good.
I'll give you that.
Not great.
Just...pretty good.
What can I say?
It's a gift.
Yeah.
Here's the thing, Glass.
I played the same game myself
so normally, I wouldn't tell you
not to run your little scam.
- It's not a scam.
- 'It's a scam.'
We both know it's a scam,
but you stepped over a line.
This is police business. There's
a child's life at stake here.
Yeah, that's why I'm here.
You don't want to push me.
Back off this woman.
Get out of here right now
or you're gonna regret it.
I can understand
your frustration.
You had the vision
and you lost it, and I..
...I can't think
of anything more horrible.
You got a lot of nerve.
Maybe I've got you
pegged all wrong.
Maybe you're
a kidnapper too.
Yeah. No, he's not the balloon
man. I talked to Van Pelt.
During the first two abductions,
he was in New York and Atlanta
giving a presentation
before a 100 people.
Actually, it was 200.
Yeah.
Excuse me.
We don't have time for you
to have a feud with this guy.
I-it's like your conscience
is battling your old self.
There's no upside.
You think
that's why I'm here?
- That's intriguing.
- 'We have to go.'
A boy's life's on
the line and this man could
take another kid and kill him.
Yeah. Let's go then.
So I've been trolling
pedophile chat rooms.
There's this one guy, Charlie95.
Something's up with him.
He's too eager to chat
about the first two boys.
- Are you tracking him?
- Yep.
IT says any minute now.
Tell me you've
got something better.
Been looking
into this black SUV
the power company guy saw,
cross-checking to see
if any registered
pedophiles own one.
- 'It's thin.'
- Yeah, it's thin.
We're not gonna make it, are we?
Jane, feel free
to jump in any time.
I'm thinking.
[inhales deeply]
The second boy, Reggie,
it's bothering me.
If he reached the bus stop
just three minutes later
he would've arrived at
the same time as his classmate
and Reggie would
still be alive today.
- 'Is that bad luck?'
- Or planning.
Maybe the killer was watching
for the perfect moment.
How could anyone have
watched the first kid?
His bus stop's not
visible from the main road.
I've got a picture of the first
crime scene somewhere here.
Charlie95 is Brady Walton
'the power company guy
we questioned.'
- 'It can't be a coincidence.'
- 'It isn't.'
'The killer was watching
from above.'
Walton is the Balloon Man.
Oh, my God.
He was here. We had him.
Get Cho on the phone. Tell him
we're moving in immediately.
Walton's registered four guns
including an AK.
No telling how many
he's really got.
Good to know.
Here's how it's gonna work.
Van Pelt and I are gonna take
the three-four corner.
You and Cho are gonna take
the one-two.
Now be careful.
The kid could still be in there.
[machine gun firing]
You ain't gettin' me!
Not gonna happen!
[Van Pelt]
'Cho, do you copy?'
[panting]
Lisbon, we're pinned.
We're pinned
on the two side.
Take the three corner. Let me
know when you're in position.
[firing continues]
[panting]
Rigs, I got a clear path
to the front door.
Stand by.
[cocks gun]
[casings clatter]
[Walton]
'It may be too late for me,
but I ain't going to prison!'
'I ain't going quiet!'
Approaching the door.
Stand by.
[panting]
Van Pelt,
are you in position?
Van Pelt?
Screw you..
[gunshot]
Oh!
[coughs]
Everybody okay?
Find the kid.
Conner?
- Lisbon!
- 'Conner?'
[panting]
I'm alright. Walton's down.
[coughs]
Walton, stay with us.
Where's the kid? Tell us.
Where's Conner?
[strained]
How would I know?
He's lying. Gotta be.
Boss, the house is clear.
The kid's not in there.
[cell phone rings]
Hey, Jane.
We got Walton.
The kid's nowhere to be seen.
Tell Rigsby to look in his left
pocket. There should be a note.
Rigs, is there a note
in your left pants pocket?
"The Balloon Man
didn't take Conner."
Okay, so how'd he do that?
Hey. So videotape puts Brady
Walton at a 7-Eleven across town
while Conner
was being snatched.
- Damn it.
- Yeah.
Walton killed those two boys,
but didn't take Conner.
- We've got a copycat.
- So Jane was right.
[sighs]
Jane was right.
I gotta find Lisbon.
She's not in her office.
Hey, Grace,
well done anyway.
You took down
a seriously bad guy.
Another day,
another dollar.
Hey.
You okay?
Yeah. I feel
pretty good actually.
I'm starting to enjoy
shooting people.
[chuckles]
Gotcha.
- No, you didn't.
- Yes, I did.
You didn't get me.
Yeah, I did.
Walton has an alibi
for Conner's abduction.
- 'Hmm.'
- How did you know?
Well, something was just,
uh, a little off.
The other kids Walton killed
were older. They had dark hair.
- That's it?
- Just a good guess.
Why the hell
didn't you tell me?
Would you have done
anything differently?
Probably not. Walton was bad.
[slurps]
Then there's no need
to be cranky.
So who took Conner?
Don't know.
I'm still working on that.
- Is he alive?
- I hope so.
So we're back to square one
on this one.
First principle, motive.
Why would somebody vanish
a nine-year-old boy?
To hide evidence
he was beaten, maybe?
Abuse? Meh. No.
This has the whiff of something
more tangled, more interesting.
Money? We dismissed it because
there was no ransom demand
but there's other ways
to get money.
Conner inherited half
your husband's estate.
Isn't that right, Mrs. Flint?
Twenty million dollars?
Uh, uh, yes. It's being held
in a trust until he turns 30.
- Why?
- Who inherits if Conner dies?
He's.. No, he's just
a little boy.
He's not supposed to
die at all. Wh..
According to the terms
of the trust
you get everything.
Are you saying I..
that I killed my son?
The thing is, we looked
into everybody
in the family's financials.
Jonathan's worth $30 million
but you need money,
don't you, Mrs. Flint?
I-I don't..
I don't know what you mean.
I-I don't know what
I'm doing in this room.
According to the bank
you have $100,000
in credit card debt.
You've spent everything your
husband left you, and then some.
I've made some..
some bad investments
and I-I'm just
not very good with numbers.
I always relied
on James for that.
Could you please sit down?
Thank you.
That must have been
really stressful for you
your financial situation.
It's very embarrassing.
I mean, I couldn't
even tell Deke.
[knock on door]
Uh, could you excuse me?
Her family's here
with a lawyer.
We gotta charge her
or kick her.
Maybe you snapped.
It's understandable.
One weak moment,
and you saw a way out.
If something were
to happen to Conner
all your problems
would be over.
If something happens to Conner,
my lifewill beover.
Please, please..
Just help me find my boy.
[sighs]
- Are you okay?
- I'm fine. I'm fine. Hi.
[kisses]
What did they want?
Well, they a-asked me a lot
of questions about money.
[Lisbon]
'Mom's clean.
What are you thinking?'
[Jane]
'What was I thinking?'
I was thinking, uh...
Love is strange..
...and I was thinking
about a sandwich.
You know who else is profiting
from Conner's abduction?
- Who?
- Nathan Glass.
He alibied out
for the first two kids
but not Conner,
and maybe he took him
to cement his relationship
with Beth.
Well, he's certainly
heartless enough.
- We'll get him in a room.
- No, he'll just clam up.
What if we get him
to lead us to Conner?
That would be nice.
Boss, forensics came back
with the labs
on Conner's school bus stop.
Nothing?
Nope. The only weird thing is
there were traces
of white fir pollen
'where they think
Conner was grabbed.'
No white firs there.
Just pines.
- Alright. Thanks.
- Okay.
Yes. Got it.
[clatters]
Thank you, Caroline.
[sighs]
Let's get out of here.
Any news?
No, uh, listen,
I just wanted to say
I'm sorry for everything
that's happened.
- What's the matter?
- Nothing.
- Uh, bye.
- Wait. Wait. No, Patrick.
- When you grabbed my hand--
- Nothing happened at all.
- Something happened. Are you--
- No!
No, no. Are you
sensing something?
- No. No.
- Liar. Liar.
I see..
There's a face.
What's wrong?
It's Conner.
- It is?
- Oh, my God.
Jane, what are you doing?
I don't understand.
He's standing right there
in front of me.
[panting]
Lisbon.
- What is it?
- Lisbon, I don't like this.
- I don't like this.
- What's going on?
'No. There's someone there.
I see someone.'
Oh, wait. Wait.
There's someone.
Are.. they're following.
They're gonna catch me.
Sweating.
- His abductor?
- Oh, come on. This is crap.
Shh.
[breathing heavily]
I can't do it.
He's just a little boy.
I-I..
Conner. Conner.
Yes, yes. Conner. Conner.
Where is Conner?
There's a.. There's a light,
and it dances.
It just dance..
It dances on the water.
- It's dancing on the water.
- Oh, god.
- It's so beautiful.
- Conner. Conner's near water.
It's a strong smell, like..
...spicy, like Christmas--
Pine trees?
It's like pine trees,
but different.
Oh, and the bad.. There's
a bad smell, a bad taste.
Pungent.
Gunpowder.
Yeah, it's gunpowder.
It's bad.
[gasps]
[exhales deeply]
And you can almost see
the house.
He's just surrounded.
There's wood, wood and trees.
And-and..
[sighs]
Uh, he's in a cabin.
It's not a cabin.
No, it's like a, uh,
it's smaller, like a sh..
Oh! I'm tired.
Jane. Wake up.
'Jane, wake up!'
- 'What happened?'
- 'I don't know.'
I was gonna ask you that.
That was weird.
- I knew you could sense him.
- Please don't touch me.
Get all of your neighbors
and volunteers.
'Karl, I want you to call
the sheriff's department.'
Cho'll lead the search
of the state forest.
We'll start
at the Flint property line.
One hour. Come on.
[pants and sighs]
See, that's how you do
a psychic reading?
[clicks tongue]
[blinds rattle]
Whew.
[yawns]
[birds chirping]
Drop the knife!
Do it now!
Are you deaf?
Drop it, Flint!
I wasn't gonna hurt him,
I swear.
Get on your knees.
Put your hands on your head.
[opens latch]
[clicks]
Conner, I'm agent Van Pelt.
I'm from the CBI.
I'm here to help you.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
Ohh.
[Jonathan]
'I was just looking for Conner.'
This is all
a big misunderstanding.
You wanted Conner dead.
You grabbed him, made it look
like a child murderer did it.
Which part are
we misunderstanding?
But you couldn't
bring yourself
to kill your baby brother
face-to-face
so you left him
in that duck blind.
No food, no water,
no chance.
No, that's not true.
Why would I want Conner dead?
I don't need his money.
Love.
You are in love with Beth.
- What are you thinking?
- Uh, I was thinking..
Love is strange.
Jane called this one right.
He was in love with Beth, only
she didn't see him that way.
- How was he gonna change that?
- Kill her kid.
Be there to comfort her,
pick the broken pieces.
- No! I always planned--
- 'Always planned what?'
What did you plan?
[sighs]
I had always planned to go get
him and bring him back.
Play the hero.
Put on a mask,
kidnap Conner
then go find him later,
rescue him.
And then Beth is filled
with gratitude
and falls
into your manly arms.
- Bingo.
- That's a dumb plan.
I was going
to bring him back!
So what was the knife for?
I..
I didn't..
Planning is easy.
Reality's a bit harder.
What if Conner recognized you?
What if Jane is psychic?
Better just to make a clean
break and kill the kid, right?
He is.
Jane's psychic.
Isn't he?
Nah.
We followed you.
You led us to Conner.
No.
No, no, no.
That's impossible.
The stuff Mr. Jane said,
that he saw Conner.
The-the trees,
the smell of gunpowder
near a-a body of water..
It was all accurate.
How the hell did he do it?
- Mom. Mommy!
- Hi.
[crying]
Hi, baby.
Oh, baby, you're home.
You're home. You're safe.
Yeah, welcome home, buddy.
'Ohh. Mm.'
Look at you. Oh, my God.
Oh. I'm just happy, okay?
You want some French toast?
I made you some French toast.
- French toast is for breakfast.
- It's a special occasion.
Come on.
[sniffles]
Congratulations, Mr. Jane.
Oh. Yes, yes.
You son of a bitch.
You trying to steal my action?
Mr. Glass,
nice to finally meet you.
And you got no action. You're
a disgrace to the profession.
That contact
you faked with Conner..
Weak. Weak.
Bite me.
That gag was seamless.
You see how she fell for it?
[high-pitched]
"Oh. Mo mo. Mo mo."
[laughs]
[chuckles]
Thanks. That should do it.
Excuse me?
[clears throat]
And, uh, stop.
[beeps]
[Glass on tape]
"Oh. Mo mo. Mo mo."
[laughs]
Bye.
Don't leave.
I won't.
We'll be right over there.
[sheets rustle]
So..
You gonna tell me
how you did it?
Everything you said came true..
...but it was a trick,
wasn't it?
Yeah.
How?
Well, um..
Being held not far from home..
...the police shut down
the roads
immediately
after Conner's abduction.
The lake..
There's always a body
of water nearby, always.
Trees, leaves, earth..
There was, uh,
white fir pollen
found at, uh,
at the bus stop
and where could you hide
anyone in a forest?
Hunting blind,
hence the gunpowder smell.
And I was watching
Jonathan's face the whole time.
I could see whenever
my guesses landed.
[sighs]
Of course.
Elegant.
You know,
all those years ago
when you were a psychic
and...you were lying to me
telling me about my future--
Yeah, I'm-I'm very sorry
about that.
Don't apologize.
You tried to tell me.
You deceived me, sure..
[sighs]
...but you gave me hope.
Thank you for that.
Goodbye, Patrick.
Bye, Beth.
[sighs]
- Cheer up.
- Oh, I'm cheery.
You heard her.
You gave her hope.
I didn't give her hope.
I sold her hope.
I think hope is worth it
at any price.
What, are you running
for office now?
Okay, you know what?
You're a wicked charlatan,
and you're going to hell then.
That's more like it. I'll save
you a seat by the fire.
Oh, I'm not going to hell.
- Oh, you're not?
- 'No.'
You've made
other arrangements, huh?
- 'Mm-hmm.'
- 'Yeah, where are you going?'
[Lisbon]
'Do you really wanna have
this conversation?'
'You ready for some,
uh, theological talk here?'
[Jane]
'I don't reallywanna
have that conversation.'
[Lisbon]
'You wanted to feel better,
not worse.'
[Jane]
'I'm gonna recline
and have a little sleep.'
[Lisbon]
'Okay.'